<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Cambodia on Jason Omedes</title>
    <link>https://jasoromir.github.io/portfolio/blog_travel/3cambodia/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Cambodia on Jason Omedes</description>
    <generator>Source Themes academia (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>Jason Omedes &amp;copy; {year}</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 09 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	    <atom:link href="https://jasoromir.github.io/portfolio/blog_travel/3cambodia/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Border</title>
      <link>https://jasoromir.github.io/portfolio/blog_travel/3cambodia/border/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 May 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jasoromir.github.io/portfolio/blog_travel/3cambodia/border/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;day-1-corruption-in-the-border-250319&#34;&gt;Day 1: Corruption in the border🤑 (25/03/19)&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I had read that in the border between Lao and Cambodia there was some corruption, but I could not expect that this day would become one of my &amp;ldquo;go-to stories&amp;rdquo; to tell.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was traveling with my friends Tanguy and Lisa, we had booked a minivan with a bunch of other people that would take us to the border and from there another van would pick us up to go to Siem Reap.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When we stopped at the border, one of the agents asked me for my passport and 40$ to process my visa on arrival. I knew for a fact that the real price was 30$ and they were just trying to scam tourists, but if you were persistent you could get away with the real price. It was not only about saving 10$, but a matter of principles of not letting them get away with these illegal actions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I let the people of my bus know what they were trying to do and most of us rallied together in a peaceful protest. They attempted to close the office window but 3 of us put our arms through to avoid that.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I believe they were getting tired and were about to give in, when another bus packed with British people stopped by. This time the agent ask them from 50$, and they all paid🤦‍♂️. We tried to block the window so they could not get their passports before we got our stamps too, which resulted in an increased agitation of the border agents.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From that moment, everything escalated quickly. At some point, they attempted to stab my hand with a pen so I removed my hand from the office window.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Which lead to me calling them a Mafia😤. I don&amp;rsquo;t know what that word triggered, but their eyes went crazy, they all left the office, came to me, pushed me around and grabbed me. Then they address to the group of people of my bus -&amp;ldquo;Either you pay now! Or we out your leader in a dark room&amp;rdquo;. For a couple of seconds, I got all excited about being called the leader and I was willing to take one for the team, and have one more experience to tell. But soon I remembered the stories of people who enter one of these prisons and never leave.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We all decided to pay, but when it was my turn, the officer catapulted my passport back to my face -&amp;ldquo;you not pass! You bad people&amp;rdquo;. What?😮&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Not knowing what to do I screamed to my group - &amp;ldquo;guys, they won&amp;rsquo;t let me pass, tell the bus driver to wait a bit for me&amp;rdquo;. The officers would not talk to me, so not know it what to do I sat down and started to read a book, to calm myself and show them I was not leaving.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thirty minutes later, one of the agents came to me and told me my bus was going to leave, which meant I would lose way more than the 10$ they wanted to get from me, and that if I wanted to pass and get it I should &amp;ldquo;pull down my pants&amp;rdquo; and tell the other agents that &amp;ldquo;I was very sorry for all the troubles I had caused, that I am a horrible person, an awful tourist, and that I would behave properly and respect the laws of their country&amp;rdquo;&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After several hours fighting for our rights, I was exhausted, I swallowed my pride and agreed on their terms. The worst thing was to find out, they had lied to me once more. And after crossing the border, we all had to wait at least 2 more hours until our ride came to pick us up😒&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;P.S. The picture is not from the actual darkroom, but I have no pics from Cambodia&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://jasoromir.github.io/portfolio/hobbies/travelling&#34;&gt;Go back to travel directory&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Kampot</title>
      <link>https://jasoromir.github.io/portfolio/blog_travel/3cambodia/kampot/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 May 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jasoromir.github.io/portfolio/blog_travel/3cambodia/kampot/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;day-20-i-lose-it-all-110419&#34;&gt;DAY 20: I lose it ALL🙈 (11/04/19)&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It was biking time again. This time &amp;ldquo;only&amp;rdquo; 150km to reach my next destination, Kampot.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Compared with the first 2 days, biking had become a bit less painful. Around 100km in, I laid down in an empty bamboo hut next to the road. Several local men saw me and came towards me. I thought I was in trouble but they wanted to invite me for drinks and to play karaoke with them. They didn&amp;rsquo;t accept a NO for an answer but I was not able to sing their Khmer songs either🤷🏻‍♂️. After a couple of hours, I told them I had to go or I wouldn&amp;rsquo;t make it to Kampot, but they were drunk and didn&amp;rsquo;t want me to go. I had to lie, promising I would visit them back on my return.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That harmless lie turned my life into Hell, as a couple of Km later the road turned into pebbles and sand making it almost impossible to ride. On top of that, cars and trucks would pass raising huge clouds of dust that swallowed me. I thought that would be over soon, but I couldn&amp;rsquo;t be more wrong. I had to go sooo slow that soon it was dark, which made it even more difficult and dangerous. I couldn&amp;rsquo;t stop dreaming of reaching the town and taking a warm shower.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When I finally made it, found a hostel, and asked them for a room, I discovered that things still could go worse. I HAD LOST MY WALLET on the road! I had no phone, no money, no cards, nothing! No money meant no room, so I could already see myself selling my body for cash. In the worst-case scenario, I had a note written in Khmer saying something like &amp;ldquo;Please, I don&amp;rsquo;t know where to sleep, let me stay in a cell tonight&amp;rdquo; that I should show to the police in case of emergency.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But before giving up, I took my dynamo flashlight and decided to ride back very slowly through the shitty and dirty road I had come by. I had to stop every few minutes to charge up my torch and all the cars were beeping at me, but after persisting for 2 hours I found the wallet.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That night I deserved a hotel room. I asked the manager to email me a picture of my dirty looks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The rest of the days in Kampot were quite nice tho. Probably one of the nicest places in Cambodia, I wouldn&amp;rsquo;t have minded spending more time there but I had not many days to spare.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://jasoromir.github.io/portfolio/hobbies/travelling&#34;&gt;Go back to travel directory&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Kep</title>
      <link>https://jasoromir.github.io/portfolio/blog_travel/3cambodia/kep/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 May 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jasoromir.github.io/portfolio/blog_travel/3cambodia/kep/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;day-23-kep-and-pepper-130419&#34;&gt;DAY 23: Kep and pepper (13/04/19)&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Days in Kampot were very nice. I had spotted an amazing place where I was going for breakfast every day. One of these mornings, I thought it would be nice to let my family know I was still alive so I asked the owner to let me log in on Facebook using his phone. After several minutes of explaining to him my phone got stolen, he accepted.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To my surprise, I had a message from my French friends with whom I had crossed the Laos-Cambodia border, saying that just today they were coming to a nearby town, Kep. I texted them back but before getting a response, I took my bike and rode to Kep.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I didn&amp;rsquo;t know how I would find them, but I trusted in the universe. And in fact, all the stars aligned so I would find them in the Kep crab market🦀. I was planning to get some fresh seafood there, but they convinced me to go with them to eat &amp;ldquo;the best chicken with pepper ever&amp;rdquo; and then visit a nearby French pepper plantation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In &amp;ldquo;La Plantation&amp;rdquo;, they gave us a free tour, including an exotic pepper tasting. It turns out that the pepper harvested in Kep is one of the best in the world. They had more than 7 varieties of pepper from which I especially liked one with barbeque flavor and another that can be eaten as a snack. My 2 friends went back to Kep and I convinced them to come visit me in Kampot the next day, as it would be my last day.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the morning I played stupid again, attempting to cycle up a mountain to visit the Bokor National Park. Many locals riding motorbikes encouraged me, but halfway through I realized I was too dead and I knew the next day I had another 120km waiting for me. At least riding downhill was a lot of fun🎢&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When I met my friends at night, I was surprised with a huge celebration. I didn&amp;rsquo;t know cuz I didn&amp;rsquo;t have a phone, but that was the first day of Songkran, which is like a New Years&#39; celebration in all the SE of Asia. People were euphoric dancing, screaming, and throwing water at each other. Also, a couple of firefighter trucks were in the main Durian square spraying everybody. We joined them for a while but I didn&amp;rsquo;t stay long, as the next day I was riding towards the paradisiac island of Koh Rong🏝️&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://jasoromir.github.io/portfolio/hobbies/travelling&#34;&gt;Go back to travel directory&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Koh Rong</title>
      <link>https://jasoromir.github.io/portfolio/blog_travel/3cambodia/kohrong/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 May 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jasoromir.github.io/portfolio/blog_travel/3cambodia/kohrong/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;day-25-castaway-120419&#34;&gt;DAY 25: Castaway (12/04/19)&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was going to paradise. That was the mental picture that kept me motivated during the intense last ride towards Sihanoukville. What used to be a must-go laid back destination for backpackers has become a smelly dumpster with huge buildings and casinos for Chinese people.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I needed to find a boat to get me to the islands asap. I didn&amp;rsquo;t want to stay there even one night but it was getting late and they didn&amp;rsquo;t let me bring the bike to the island. I had to pay a couple of guys working in the parking of a hotel so they would take care of it while I was gone.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In Koh Rong, there were no roads, no paths, only sand. No wonder they wouldn&amp;rsquo;t take the bike, it would be useless there. I walked down the beach asking in different places if they had a free room, but given it was &amp;ldquo;New Year&amp;rdquo; the prices were insane, over 100€ per night. I thought I would have to sleep under a palm tree but luckily I found an affordable dorm.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The island was amazing. Especially for its main attraction: bioluminescent plankton. However, I was completely miserable. Days were long and hot and I didn&amp;rsquo;t know what to do.
One day I fell asleep reading a book in a hammock inside the water. I burned myself completely. I was de nourished and devastated both physically and mentally from the long hours riding under the sun. I looked like a skinny dirty monkey with my skin peeling off. I felt lonely and out of purpose.
I missed home, my family and my friends. I was living in paradise but in my mind, I was not there. I started to wonder if this was not for me and it was time to go back. The only thing that made me stay was my sister telling me that she wanted to come and visit me for my birthday (that was about to come). That gave me a sense of purpose: I would plan the perfect trip for her.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A few days later I went back to find my bike. I wasn&amp;rsquo;t completely sure if it would still be there or if the weird men would have sold it for profit, but they were legit. I was not willing to ride back so I put the bike on a bus, and went back to Siem Reap. I returned the bike and spent the next few days planning what to do with my dear sister. Back to Thailand we go!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://jasoromir.github.io/portfolio/hobbies/travelling&#34;&gt;Go back to travel directory&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>On the road</title>
      <link>https://jasoromir.github.io/portfolio/blog_travel/3cambodia/road/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 May 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jasoromir.github.io/portfolio/blog_travel/3cambodia/road/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;day-14-the-challenge--060419&#34;&gt;DAY 14: The Challenge🚲  (06/04/19)&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I woke up while it was still dark (to avoid riding long hours under the burning sun) only to find out the gate of the orphanage was locked, and I was forced to wake up everyone so I could start riding.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After a last-minute and emotive farewell, I was super motivated to ride fast with direction to Pnom Penh. I had 330km to cover and I was planning to make it in two days. In my head that made a lot of sense, 160km/D at around 20 km/h, I would have to ride around 8 hours and I would have plenty of time for a lunch break and a nap. The reality turned out to be quite different, especially considering that during the previous months I had barely done any exercise.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I started very energized, but after a couple of hours, my legs and butt began to burn. I stopped to rest in the playground of a school. Suddenly, a little kid showed up and through signs guided me towards one of the classrooms. There I found a bunch of 10ish yo kids having a party. They couldn&amp;rsquo;t speak English but still invited me to food and sodas. It was a nice way to recharge.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While riding again, I found out that Cambodian towns are just a bunch of houses piled at the sides of the main road, and most local shops wouldn&amp;rsquo;t sell water or food to me because I only had big bills and they didn&amp;rsquo;t have change. Thus, I had to keep riding for several hours to find a restaurant. At that time, my legs were in so much pain that they immediately went numb, I felt down and had to crawl to the nearest chair almost crying from the pain.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It got dark and I got lost. My only map was a drawing I had done before departing and in Cambodia there are no signs on the road. How I made it to my bed? It&amp;rsquo;s a long story involving a dirty road, being chased by dogs, police who didn&amp;rsquo;t know how to use google maps, and a special note. And that was only half of the way to PP, the next day it would be more of the same.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Best of the ride:&lt;/strong&gt; Countless Cambodian kids running out of their houses chasing me to say HELLO🙋🏻‍♀️.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Worst part:&lt;/strong&gt; Cars and trucks beeping at me (to say hello?) and so much soreness!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;⚠️These are not my pictures (my phone was stolen), but they are a good representation of my stories.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://jasoromir.github.io/portfolio/hobbies/travelling&#34;&gt;Go back to travel directory&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Orphanage</title>
      <link>https://jasoromir.github.io/portfolio/blog_travel/3cambodia/orphanage/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 May 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jasoromir.github.io/portfolio/blog_travel/3cambodia/orphanage/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;day-6-cambodian-orphans-030419&#34;&gt;Day 6: Cambodian orphans (03/04/19)&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After getting lost a couple times with my bike, I finally reached the &amp;ldquo;Bridges Cambodia International&amp;rdquo; orphanage.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As I didn&amp;rsquo;t have a phone, I hadn&amp;rsquo;t informed anybody of my arrival. When the kids saw me arrive they barely reacted. Especially, the girls gave me a very cold stare. I was not expecting a party on my behalf, and I know I didn&amp;rsquo;t look very clean, but still, I had imagined a warmer welcome.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Soon, I realized that these kids have been living here for a long time, and volunteers come and go all the time, breaking their young hearts every time.
As a consequence, most of them have learned to defend themselves being stone cold. Personally, now I wouldn&amp;rsquo;t recommend volunteering in a place like this for short periods of time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Also, the place was not what I had in mind. More than the typical orphanage you see in movies this was something similar to a farm. In fact, more than once, the kids would miss our English lessons to go feed the goats or cows on the field.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My initial plan was staying only a couple of days, but I ended up extending it to a week. During that time I tried to earn a little space in their hearts, giving them as much love as I could, trying to fix their old bikes, letting them ride mine, helping them with the early morning chores, feeding the animals, playing games and trying to inspire them to pursue their objectives in life.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some of the boys responded well and invited me to some of their activities, including taking outdoors showers with a bucket in a nearby fountain. However, the girls hated me since the first minute and there was nothing I could do to change that.
Luckily I was not alone, Sandra was the other volunteer in the school. It was good to have additional support with the kids, and she had more success than me with the girls.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am missing several anecdotes of the 7 days I spent in this place. I still have many good memories but I also remember the pain of their constant rejection of having me around. So after the 7 days, I realized it was time to go!
Also, I didn&amp;rsquo;t have much time left to visit the rest of the country so I would have to ride fast&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://jasoromir.github.io/portfolio/hobbies/travelling&#34;&gt;Go back to travel directory&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pnohm Penh</title>
      <link>https://jasoromir.github.io/portfolio/blog_travel/3cambodia/pnohmpenh/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 May 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jasoromir.github.io/portfolio/blog_travel/3cambodia/pnohmpenh/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;day-16-pnohm-penh-080419&#34;&gt;Day 16: Pnohm Penh (08/04/19)&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After two days of cycling, I made it to the capital. It was very hot and I was very exhausted so I found a hostel with a swimming pool.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I took some time to read, walk around, visit markets, and learn some history. I knew Cambodia had gone through a recent genocide, but I was not aware of all the horrors.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Barely 40 years ago, the Khmer Rouge attempted to impose an agricultural reform leading to the annihilation of 1/3 of Cambodia&amp;rsquo;s population in under 5 years. Their leader, Pol Pot, had the genius idea of killing all those people who were not farmers, including scientists, teachers, or any person who had glasses🧐.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of these killing fields has now evolved into a beautiful memorial park. Beautiful on the outside, but you can get sick while they narrate real stories of what happened there. How they were tortured and killed with tools🔨to save money on bullets. But what impacted me the most was a big tree, now covered with offerings, that was used to smash the heads of babies against.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Enough! Let&amp;rsquo;s change the flavor with another fun but sad story.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Most of the people I met only wanted to go partying or do drugs. That is not my thing so one of the nights I went for a massage to alleviate my soreness. I am cheap, so I walked through different streets until I found an amazing offer: 1hour full body massage for 7€. My spidersenses failed me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A lady came to greet me and guided me into a red room (walls, sheets, etc). That shocked me a bit, but it was ok. She asked me to take off my clothes and started the massage. It was quite bad and in &amp;lt;15min she asked me to turn around. That was a bit early but it was my first massage in Cambodia and maybe they had a different style. She started to climb up my legs rather fast. She reached a bit too high for my liking, but I was willing to trust her. That was the moment when pointing at my &amp;ldquo;D&amp;rdquo; she asked: &amp;ldquo;Happy?&amp;rdquo;
-No, no happy!
-Then, finish!
It hadn&amp;rsquo;t passed 1 hour, but I was glad to get out of there. Then a young girl passed next to me playing with her toys. It sickened me to imagine what would be the fate of that girl growing in such place.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was still exhausted but it was time to keep moving&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://jasoromir.github.io/portfolio/hobbies/travelling&#34;&gt;Go back to travel directory&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Siem Reap</title>
      <link>https://jasoromir.github.io/portfolio/blog_travel/3cambodia/siemreap/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 May 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jasoromir.github.io/portfolio/blog_travel/3cambodia/siemreap/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;day-2-khmer-empire-270319&#34;&gt;Day 2: Khmer Empire (27/03/19)&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Angkor Wat, mostly known by its appearance in the Tomb Raider movie, was supposed to be the highlight of Cambodia. And it was, but not in the expected way.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first day in Siem Reap, Tanguy, Lisa and I walked a bit around town and bought some souvenirs. Among them, I bought some blue Alibaba style pants to increase the hippie-homeless looks that I was starting to display.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That afternoon we also arranged a tuk-tuk ride that would take us the next day around Angkor Wat, and he even took us there already to see the sunset beforehand.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was staying at a different hostel, so the next morning I had to wake up very early (4 am) to meet them at their hostel and start our journey to see the sunrise at the majestic Temple. Our driver was getting late and a different tuk-tuk driver who had followed me, tried to convince us to go with him instead. He was very persistent and was getting very annoying so I told him to -fuck off- and left us in peace. He didn&amp;rsquo;t. When our driver came, we were so thrilled to lose sight of the other guy that we jumped in with haste.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I should have noticed faster, but as we were taking off, I saw the annoying driver staring at me while picking something from the floor, rushing to his tuk-tuk, and disappearing in the dark. I immediately checked my pockets, I was wearing the Alibaba pants I just bought the day before, the pockets were too wide and when I jumped in our tuk-tuk my phone had fallen. I asked our driver to go back and try to chase the other guy, but it was too late.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I didn&amp;rsquo;t want to make my friends pay for my mistake, so we end up driving to Angkor Wat. I must say that the temple complex is impressive. And given that March is the hottest month, the attraction is not as packed with tourists as it uses to. However, the heat was extenuating, and my head was more focused on how to recover my phone than in enjoying the architectonic wonder of the Khmer Empire.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Before finishing the day I start to realize the symptoms of addiction and I cannot wait till the next day to go to the police and hopefully recover my phone. How could I know things only were going to get worse&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;day-4-change-of-plans-290319&#34;&gt;DAY 4: Change of plans (29/03/19)&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For the next couple of days, I tried reporting the theft of my phone to the police, but no fucks were given. Someone suggested I should have showed them some money, but I didn&amp;rsquo;t want to push my luck and end up in another dark room.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Also, I was experiencing the withdrawal symptoms of phone addiction😵. In a different case, this could have been therapeutic, but right now the phone was my life.
Nowadays, a backpacker🎒uses the phone for everything, contacting family and friends, navigating through cities, documenting the trip with pictures, booking transportation and accommodation, or even basic stuff like checking the time or setting an alarm.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In sights of the impossibility of recovering my phone, I had to decide whether buying a local phone (but I didn&amp;rsquo;t trust those and they were not that cheap) or ordering one on-line. But I already had lost many days to stay even longer in Siem Reap waiting for the phone. So I decided I would embrace the old way, I would travel for one month with no TECH!📵&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But in my delusion that was not challenging enough, on top of that I would rent a bicycle🚴‍♂️ (remember we are in the hottest month of the year and I have not exercised for months) and I would ride through the country visiting random villages and staying to sleep in houses of random people&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was committed, so I visited several bicycle rental stores until I found one that agreed on my idea (most of them thought I was crazy and they would never see their bike again). I also went to buy some patches, an extra tire, and an inflator, just in case. I bought a small notebook, a watch, and a pre-COVID face mask for the dust on the road.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was already mentally prepared to go on the adventure when I met Facundo, and Argentinian guy of my hostel that told me about his experience volunteering in a nearby orphanage. It sounded interesting so I thought my long tour could wait and I would spend a couple days in the orphanage too.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The night before going to the orphanage, I went out with Facundo to the Pub he used to work. There, I met an interesting Spanish guy and we ended up talking about bizarre topics such as hugging trees&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://jasoromir.github.io/portfolio/hobbies/travelling&#34;&gt;Go back to travel directory&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
