<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Laos on Jason Omedes</title>
    <link>https://example.com/blog_travel/2laos/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Laos on Jason Omedes</description>
    <generator>Source Themes academia (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>Copyright &amp;copy; {year}</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 09 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	    <atom:link href="https://example.com/blog_travel/2laos/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>4000 islands</title>
      <link>https://example.com/blog_travel/2laos/4000islands/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 May 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/blog_travel/2laos/4000islands/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;day-25-4000-islands-210319&#34;&gt;DAY 25: 4000 Islands (21/03/19)&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My last stop in Laos was Si Phan Don a.k.a. The 4000 islands.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This archipielago is located in the border between Laos and Cambodia, and even though there may exist 4000 island or more🏝️, there are 3 that are way bigger than the rest (Don Khong, Don Det and Don Khon).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I read that Don Khong is barely visited by tourists, so I decided to start with that one to recover from my recent injuries. In fact, there was not much to do around but lay on a hammock and read books📖.
I believe we were only 2 foreigners in the whole island, as the next morning I was notified that the other girl was leaving and I should leave too or who knows when another boat would come🤷🏻‍♂️&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I joined her to go to Don Det where I stumbled upon my French friends Lisa and Tanguy. We stayed in Mama Tanon&amp;rsquo;s, a friendly local lady&amp;rsquo;s guesthouse, where we spent most of our days lying down in mats with views to the river, eating cheap food and drinking fruit shakes🍍.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of those days, we rented bicycles and rode around Don Det and Don Khong. It was a hot day and the beaches that we were expecting to find were quite dirty. When we returned to our bungalows I was so thirsty and hungry that I decided to buy a watermelon and eat the whole thing in one sitting🍉. Not the best idea, and not the best night (search Watermelon side effects for more details💩).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The last day, we booked a kayaking tour around the 4000 island of the Mekong, we sightsee the last Irrawaddy dolphins of the area and the sacred waterfalls Phapheng Waterfall (brief story in the comments).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As we were leaving to Cambodia, Mama Tanon had made bracelets for us to wish us luck. Little did I know&amp;hellip;🤦‍♂️&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the middle of the river, next to the waterfall there used to be a tree, Manikhot. This historic and sacred tree, has been staying in Khone Phapheng Falls for more than 2,000 years until it’s dead on 19th March 2012.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The reason was unknown. Lao people believed that the tree is able to give life and death. It’s believed that the core of Manikhoth can make things die and the top part of the tree can bring dead things back to life.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Every Buddha days from October to March, there are a bunch of white egrets flying around Manikhoth tree three rounds before landing on the branches and trees nearby. It’s said that the egrets are showing respect.
After its death in 2012, the Manikhoth could not be brought up from the water due to the heavy flow of water in Khone Phapheng Falls.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/hobbies/travelling&#34;&gt;Go back to travel directory&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hauy Xai</title>
      <link>https://example.com/blog_travel/2laos/huayxai/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 May 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/blog_travel/2laos/huayxai/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;day-1-tarzan-life-24022019&#34;&gt;Day 1: Tarzan life (24/02/2019)&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The trip from Thailand to Laos was very straight forward, with not many remarks. Get on a bus, walk to the border, pay, wait for another bus, cross a bridge, walk, one more bus, and rest.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Huay Xai, the town at the border, has not much to offer as a town. Most people stop here to take a slow boat through the Mekong that will take them to Luang Prabang. I was tempted to do it, but a friend from the farm (@jackedz89 ) had recommended me something different, the gibbon experience.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It was a bit pricy, but as a &amp;lsquo;Tarzan wannabe&amp;rsquo; I had to try it, and you know what YOLO!🐒 For the next couple of days, we would be hiking in the jungle, moving around using zip lines to cross between mountains. And we would spend the night in a treehouse. Exciting!!🤩&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I remember that soon after starting the hike through the jungle I saw a goat with two babies. They got scared and the mum goat ran away. One of the babies, decided that I would be her new mum and started to follow me (my own mum used to call me &amp;ldquo;mountain goat&amp;quot;🐐 when I was younger, so I understand the animal confusion). Luckily we found the real mum and continued our way.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ziplining over the trees was quite exciting, but there were too many safety rules and at some point became repetitive. I decided to spice things up a little bit trying different flying postures, but the guides didn&amp;rsquo;t seem to like it🙈.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We arrived at the tree-house to enjoy the sunset from the top. Followed by a quite tasty dinner, and night of games. I especially connected with two amazing couples Kasia &amp;amp; Arame, and Bhav &amp;amp; Rajvi.
They had been backpacking for a longer time and served me as inspiration for the subsequent months of my journey (Bhav also had a quite long beard and inspired me to grow mine🧔).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Spending the night in the treehouse was pretty cool but also a bit scary, as that night there was a storm and I could feel the tree shaking. Plus, some rats invaded the house overnight to see if they could steal some food leftovers, and we could hear them running around.🐁&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The next morning we woke up early to see the sunrise, and the guides tried to take us to an area where sometimes you can see Gibbons (as expected there was no luck).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In exchange, they showed us a special bark of a tree that is used for fireworks (the video is slowed down, but in real-time you could see the fire in the air for a couple seconds too).
After more than 17 long ziplines, we were all exhausted and happy to go back to civilization to keep our adventures going somewhere else.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/hobbies/travelling&#34;&gt;Go back to travel directory&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Luang Namtha</title>
      <link>https://example.com/blog_travel/2laos/luangnamtha/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 May 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/blog_travel/2laos/luangnamtha/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;day-4-nutritious--delicious-27219&#34;&gt;DAY 4: Nutritious &amp;amp; Delicious (27/2/19)&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As I came back from the jungle, I had to replenish my energies. So while I was planning on how to get to the northern villages of Laos, I bought a 0.5kg bucket of nutritious oreo ice cream
Perfect snack that I finished in less than 5 min, as it was melting with the crazy heat and I couldn&amp;rsquo;t keep it for later.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I decided that my next destination would be Luang Namtha. When the bus came, after several hours waiting for it, and I stepped inside&amp;hellip; No seats. What? It was a sleeping bus, the &amp;lsquo;best&amp;rsquo; part is that the beds are quite small, and on top of that you have to share them, so much fun!! Apart from that, the views during the long ride were astonishing. Sadly, I couldn&amp;rsquo;t recover any of those pictures. I could recover something better tho. I don&amp;rsquo;t usually share pictures of food, but I know you all will be jealous of my nutritious bowl of silkworms pupae. Yummy!😋&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Until that point, I thought I was the only foreigner on the bus, but a French guy, Baptiste, joined me for the silkworm feast.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hours later we arrived at Luang Namtha bus station, which is several kilometers away from the town. And at those later hours, we were just fresh meat for the tuk-tuk hyenas trying to rip us off to take us to town.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The next day, we agreed on booking a 2day survival experience package together that would start early the next morning. For the rest of the day, I rented a bicycle and rode South. I remember how I started the ride with a feeling of solitude, but after a few minutes of riding the bike🚴, I wouldn&amp;rsquo;t stop meeting kids with big smiles surprised by seeing a European in their small poor villages.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I ended up chilling with a few of them for sunset next to a river where a fisherman was trying to catch something for dinner. I couldn&amp;rsquo;t communicate with them at all, but they seemed to enjoy my company. Riding back to the guesthouse the feeling of solicitude had flipped to one of the most vibrant and emotionally filling moments of my trip🥰&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Note: I couldn&amp;rsquo;t recover the pictures of these days so I include photos that resemble my memories of what happened.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;##DAY 6: Survival Experience (01/03/19)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To become a real Tarzan I had to learn how to survive in the jungle. I couldn&amp;rsquo;t be more excited about the experience that was about to come.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We would spend the next couple of days hiking through the protected jungle of Nam Ha, learning about edible plants🌱, collecting food🍱, and building our own tent to sleep under🏕️.
Of the two guides that came with us, only one spoke English, but both were extremely amazing and complemented each other with their skills.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of them would tell us stories, teach us about their religion (animism) based on the existence of spirits in all our surroundings, and gave us to try different stuff to eat from whatever we found around. That was my first time to eat a handful of giant red ants🐜 (they taste like lemon).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The other one was very skilled at building stuff, most of them using bamboo🎍🐼. Apparently, there are many kinds. With one kind, he helped us building walking sticks, another type you can eat it, and with others, you can for example build a &amp;lsquo;bong&#39;🤣. From all the jungles I have visited so far, Nam Ha has been the one that brought me the closest feeling of being inside Jurassic Park.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It would not have surprised me to find a T-Rex randomly walking around🦖. When the sunset was getting close it was time to start building our tents. As you can guess the main components were bamboo for the structure but also cut in very thin slices we used it as strings. And the final touch a couple of banana leaves for the roof and the floor.
After the tent was finished, we got some thicker bamboo and used it as pots for cooking and plates to serve the meal. And for dessert, the guides went to the river and got us crabs and small fish using only a machete.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The experience was great, but the night was horrible. I could have never expected that sleeping on the floor of a jungle would be so cold and uncomfortable 🙄&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Back in Luang Namtha one of the guides came for dinner with Batiste and me. We played petanque (Lao favorite sport), sang in a karaoke, and he told us more stories about how he built his own house by himself, and about how Lao people don&amp;rsquo;t care much about the physical appearance but the feelings of the heart. It would have been a beautiful message if it wasn&amp;rsquo;t that he was getting completely wasted with two strangers while his wife was alone at home taking care of their baby. Unfortunately, Lao culture is still very male dominant.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/hobbies/travelling&#34;&gt;Go back to travel directory&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Luang Prabang</title>
      <link>https://example.com/blog_travel/2laos/luangprabang/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 May 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/blog_travel/2laos/luangprabang/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;day-12-france-in-laos-070319&#34;&gt;Day 12: France in Laos (07/03/19)&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The next stop of the trip was the buzzing Luang Prabang. Probably the most visited town in Laos, and for good reasons, as the beautiful French colonial style heritage mixed with the Lao culture makes it a unique place to be. Also, it is one of the few places in Asia in which walking down the street you can smell the delicious aroma of bakeries and handmade bread🥖.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first day, I went solo-exploring the city and after some long hours of visiting temples under the sun, I found an organization (&amp;ldquo;little brother mouse&amp;rdquo;) that aims to distribute books to little Lao kids so they get a better education. It turns out that a huge part of the Lao population cannot read at all📖. Furthermore, recently they also open their own school and were looking for people to volunteer there.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The next morning I went with them again, and they took me to the outskirts of the city where they hosted more than 200 students. We played with the kids while teaching them some English, and some of the older ones tried to teach me how to ride a monocycle (obviously I failed🤦‍♂️).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To finish the day, I met with my French friends couple, we rented bikes and went to visit a buffalo farm. The owner follows a project in which they rent buffalos from local farmers to help ensure their long-term health through adequate natal care, vaccinations, and animal husbandry. And as a plus they make delicious cheese and ice-creams&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;day-14-petanque-and-waterfalls-090319&#34;&gt;DAY 14: Petanque and Waterfalls (09/03/19)&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We jumped on our motorbikes and went to visit the iconic Kuang Si waterfalls🏞️
At the entry they had a protected playground area with rescued black bears🐻 and after a short hike we enjoyed a swim in the waterfalls.
At some point at the top, I got stuck on a swing over a small lake and for your enjoyment I attached a video of my desperate attempts of going back to the ground🤦‍♂️&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For the sunset, we drove to a small village in the outskirts of LP, where we were supposed to find a viewpoint. Instead we found a petanque place where some locals (that were supposed to be working at a hotel) asked us to join them and play some balls.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The next morning I visited the UXO museum, and my heart shrunk learning that Laos is the most bombed💣 country in the world, and that there are still many unexploded bombs around that kids confuse with toys and get their lives ruined.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We finished our last day in Luang Prabang visiting a handicrafts store where we learned how to make our own bracelets&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/hobbies/travelling&#34;&gt;Go back to travel directory&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Muang Gnoi</title>
      <link>https://example.com/blog_travel/2laos/muanggnoi/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 May 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/blog_travel/2laos/muanggnoi/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;day-10-celebrating-death-5319&#34;&gt;Day 10: Celebrating Death💀 (5/3/19)&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If Nong Khiaw was already quite and not too touristy, when the next morning we took a small boat to go to Muang Gnoi, we were surprised by how chill life was there. The whole town was basically a straight line, not bungalows next to the river. It is not very developed yet and you still can interact with locals or with kids that after school go to play to the river. Our first day we just relaxed and chill there.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For dinner, we met a young Swedish guy who met a local woman and moved there 10 years ago. He told us that we should also check the nearby traditional villages. As in one of them, someone had passed away and they were going to hold a celebration.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The next day, Tanguy, Lisa, Ella and I, went hiking to explore the surroundings. After having lunch all together in one of the villages, Lisa and Tanguy went back to Muang Gnoi. Ella and I kept hiking to the village we had been talked about. The locals we&amp;rsquo;re excited to see us, as we were the only foreigners, and they offered us accommodation for 1$/night.
Walking around the small town we met some kids that soon were fighting to call our attention. I spent the whole afternoon playing football with them (barefoot), and they changed my name to &amp;lsquo;hello&amp;rsquo;, since it was the only English word they knew how to pronounce, and kept repeating it all the time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After the game, we had a swim at the river, and went back down for dinner, where the adults had already prepared the &amp;lsquo;party&amp;rsquo;.
They offered us some local food (a bit weird) that we couldn&amp;rsquo;t reject, as the kids kept grabbing it with their hands and feeding it into our mouth🍼
On the other hand, the adults were getting completely wasted with strong rice whiskey and tried to get us drunk too. In the meantime, they played very loud traditional music and engaged in awkward dancing and flirting games.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At midnight we went to our rooms to get some sleep, but that was difficult as the loud music kept playing until the sunrise.
The next morning one of the locals offered a lift back to town on his &amp;lsquo;truck&amp;rsquo;, as we had to run to get back to Muang Gnoi in time if we wanted to catch the only boat that went back to Nong Khiaw.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/hobbies/travelling&#34;&gt;Go back to travel directory&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Nong Khaw</title>
      <link>https://example.com/blog_travel/2laos/nongkhiaw/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 May 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/blog_travel/2laos/nongkhiaw/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;day-8-over-the-clouds-030319&#34;&gt;Day 8: Over the Clouds (03/03/19)&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When I left Luang Namtha, I grabbed a mini-van not really knowing where I was going next, a small village in the North called Nong Khiaw.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Again, the bus station (as in the whole Laos) was separated from the town, but this time I had decided to walk. As I started my way a small vehicle arrived at the station, and against all the odds, my friend Ella, with whom I had separated ways more than a week ago, was there😮.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nong Khiaw is a very peaceful village located next to a river and surrounded by limestone mountains🏞️.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While we caught up, we went down to the river to enjoy the sunset, where we met a group of 4 girls who proposed us to get together to see the sunrise from a nearby mountain.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Something that I will always remember about that hike is finding a massive &amp;lsquo;river&amp;rsquo; of ants🐜, normally imperceptible, but in the silence of the night, they sounded loud as if rain was falling.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once at the top of the mountain, we waited for the sun, warm and cozy under a blanket I brought all the way up from the hostel.
When the sun started to rise, several clouds flooded the sky covering the views between our location and the town. It was magical, and definitely the most amazing view I had on my trip🌄.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On the way down I couldn&amp;rsquo;t skip the Tarzan wannabe picture, of course!🙈 The rest of the day we rented bikes to explore the surroundings, and before the end of the day, we meet a French girl who was starting a project to teach English to small kids and needed volunteers👨‍🏫.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We decided to help, and there we met a lovely French couple (Tanguy and Lisa) that would become my companions for a long part of my trip.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/hobbies/travelling&#34;&gt;Go back to travel directory&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Thakhek</title>
      <link>https://example.com/blog_travel/2laos/thakhek/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 May 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/blog_travel/2laos/thakhek/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;day-21-thakhek-loop-170319&#34;&gt;DAY 21: Thakhek Loop (17/03/19)&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;⚠️This story is just a summary but it is going to be a long one!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Going all the way to the South of Laos there is a 3day loop driving with the motorbike🛵. The scenery is gorgeous and the trail is packed with caves and limestone cliffs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The highlight of the loop is the Konglor Cave🏞️, referred to as one of the Asian wonders. It is 7km deep and filled with water so you need to ride a boat to visit the inside🚣‍♂️.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I started the ride very excited and amazed by the beautiful sights, little did I know that some awful things were about to happen😣&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;During the first day, after I have visited a couple of caves, I stopped for lunch in a waterfall area. The waterfalls were dry, but there were some pits full of water in which you could swim. At some point, a group of locals who carried huge speakers showed up.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;They invited me to join them and gave me food and snacks. Then, the males started climbing a cliff and jumping from the top. They invited me to do the same, and I had the brightest idea to record the jump with my GoPro. I was not using that much, so I thought it would be a good time. It was not! It was not properly fixed and when I hit the water it was the last time I saw it🤦‍♂️&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We tried diving but it was too deep and too blurry to see anything. Also, it was getting dark and I had to keep moving, so I decided that instead of completing the loop, the last day I would return the same way, I would buy a diving mask and I would find my GoPro📷.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By night, I arrived at a hostel near a damp. The dead trees raising from within the waters all around that area had a mystic but creepy vibe at the same time. That night we had an amazing barbeque and I met some people to ride along the next day.
We visited some more caves and stopped for lunch in a natural pool. One more time, young locals showed up, and by this time I was starting to think that jumping from heights was their traditional hobby, because as if they were monkeys, they climbed a very hight thin tree 🌴🐒 and started to show off in front of the girls.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I would have stayed longer to enjoy the spectacle, but if I wanted to make it in time to visit the Konglor Cave that day and try finding my camera the next day I had to rush!!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I jumped in my bike and drove as fast as I could, as someone just warned me the cave was closing soon. One of the last sections of the road was a straight line, a good road, no cars, so I sped up to 90km/h. I was going to make it!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Probably that thought distracted me and I couldn&amp;rsquo;t see it, a big pothole appeared in the middle of the road. By the time I wanted to react it was too late. I knew I couldn&amp;rsquo;t dodge it, so I braked and held into my bike as strong as I could. It didn&amp;rsquo;t work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Life got slow-mo and I flew like Superman. That could have been it, but it was not my time. I was wearing helmet, long pants and hard shoes, that protected me and I only ended up with some nasty scratches and a little stone stuck deep into my arm. The bike was not doing much better than me but it was still working. I patched myself and kept driving. I couldn&amp;rsquo;t let that accident be for nothing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The rest of the drive I still had to go fast, but way more careful as the road quality was getting worse, full of bumps and holes. When I finally made it to the caves, they were closing already. But I may or may have not given them some scary looks and they made an exception and let me go in. In the end, everything was worth it!!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That night I should have probably gone to a nice guesthouse. Have a good clean if my wounds, a nice bed and rest well. But I don&amp;rsquo;t follow the common sense. I decided to go for a Homestay, that means go spend the night in a house with a local family, not much electricity, shower with a bucket and a mat on the floor with a mosquito net around it👌🏻&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The kids of the family were a bit shocked when they saw all my injuries. Probably they told all their friends, as the next morning all the kids in the town were outside the house trying to have a glimpse of me. The family also helped me to fix my bike a bit, although, by its looks, I already knew I would have to pay a lot of fees when I returned it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On the way back, I had to stop in more than 10 villages to finally find a diving mask. And when I found one, the owners probably didn&amp;rsquo;t even know what it was for, but they knew it was expensive and they wanted to make some money. After a long negotiation, I still paid more than what I should have paid but I was committed to finding my GoPro.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I arrived at the waterfall area, put my mask on, removed my bloody bandages, and risking getting infected with the dirty waters I spent more than 1hour diving in. But the pit was too deep and too blurry to see anything. That was my first lesson of detachment, just let go, the camera was not of vital importance anyway. Maybe these 3 days were just packed with lessons I had to learn, and now the only thing left to do was to keep traveling&amp;hellip;🤩&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/hobbies/travelling&#34;&gt;Go back to travel directory&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Vang Vieng</title>
      <link>https://example.com/blog_travel/2laos/vangvieng/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 May 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/blog_travel/2laos/vangvieng/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;day-17-to-party-or-not-to-party-120319&#34;&gt;Day 17: To party or not to party? (12/03/19)&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To go from Luang Prabang to Vang Vieng(VV), I decided I would hitchhike. Imitating the movies I draw where I was going on a piece of paper and started to walk outside the town waving at every car👍&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After more than 3 hours walking and waiting, no luck🤦‍♂️. So I decided to walk all the way back to town and check if I could still get a minivan.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The ride was not that cheap, and best of all, the minivan engine broke in the middle of the way. One of the passengers called a friend to pick us up, but we had to agreed on paying him as much as we already had payed for the minivan🤦‍♂️&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When we arrived to VV it was already dark, I hadn&amp;rsquo;t booked a hostel and it was already past reception time, so I joined a couple guys from the van to get a bed in the hostel they were going. Big surprise, the hostel we arrived was the &amp;ldquo;party hostel&amp;rdquo; of town, just in line with my backpacking style🙈&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Apparently, VV is the biggest cluster of party in Laos. But I managed to find my way of enjoying the beautil nature that surround it. Rented a bike to visit viewpoints (highlight to Nam Xay)⛰️, a natural lagoon🗻, did kayaking on the Nam Song river🚣‍♂️, and the popular tubing through a cave.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/hobbies/travelling&#34;&gt;Go back to travel directory&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
