<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Thailand on Jason Omedes</title>
    <link>https://jasoromir.github.io/portfolio/blog_travel/1thailand/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Thailand on Jason Omedes</description>
    <generator>Source Themes academia (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>Copyright &amp;copy; {year}</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 09 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	    <atom:link href="https://jasoromir.github.io/portfolio/blog_travel/1thailand/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Bangkok</title>
      <link>https://jasoromir.github.io/portfolio/blog_travel/1thailand/bangkok/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 May 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jasoromir.github.io/portfolio/blog_travel/1thailand/bangkok/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;day-1-my-first-day-29012019&#34;&gt;Day 1: My first day (29/01/2019)&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Before starting my trip I was very excited with the decision that I had taken of going for the solo mode adventure, but at the same a bit scared of ending up alone with no idea of what to do. As we learned in &amp;ldquo;Into the wild&amp;rdquo;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;-Happiness is only real when shared.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;During the flight from Moscow to Thailand I could not sleep and the plane was quite crappy. However, it may have been for the better, because that helped me to meet who would soon become my first travel buddy , Tessa, even before having to reach Thailand.
The excitement didn&amp;rsquo;t allow me to sleep much the first night (neither the 2th or 3th, so maybe the jet lag also had a bit to do with it). At 6am I was ready to start solo exploring the city.
From the very first moment that I put a foot on the street (especially around the infamous area of #KhaoSan Rd) tens of &amp;ldquo;tuk-tuk&amp;rdquo; drivers smell my fresh Bahts and attempt to catch my attention for an overpriced drive to the main sightseeing spots. Unfortunately for them I was well aware of their scamming strategies (or that is what I thought&amp;hellip; Just wait for a couple of days)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First place I reached was the spectacular Grand Palace (#Wat Phra Kaew). One of the most famous landmarks of the city, which is as full of shiny and detailed &amp;ldquo;buildings&amp;rdquo;(chedais, prangs? I still cannot tell the correct name of these pointy things. I love them tho) as of tourists taking pictures.
It was when I was trying to sneak my phone into the no-camera allowed temple of the Emerald Buddha, when I met a super friendly Turkish girl , Meliha. That means no video, but together we started our private photo-tour around the golden temples.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We walked toward the river, and Tess joined us for a boat tour. We passed by the majestic Wat Arum and stopped in China Town.
After a good walk around the nicely decorated (chinese new year is coming) but overwhelming streets packed with small business where there is no room for pedestrians and still motorbikes manage to find a way through the crowds, we stopped for our first Thai street food. And in an attempt to spice things up I accidentally dropped a full spoon of chilly leaves&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After completing our tour through China Town we left the crowded streets and took another boat (for the ridiculous price of 0.2€) to cross the river and delight our senses with what it is my favorite temple so far, Wat Arum! It received the name after the Hindu God Aruna (God of the Sun), and it is really stunning how the detailed craftsmanship of the main &amp;ldquo;parang&amp;rdquo; glimmer reflecting the sunshine.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Despite this was my first day of what it is going to be a long traveling experience, my mindset is still that of a short vacation in which I cannot waste anytime. Therefore, the rest of the afternoon we kept going from one temple to the next one. Some of the places to remark are the colorful setupas from Wat Pho and a 46 m reclining Buddha (longest in Thailand, maybe the world?).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After exhausting most of the temples of Rattanakosin, we walked through Sananrom park direction to our hostels when we found a group of elderly Thai people dancing. I couldn&amp;rsquo;t help myself and spontaneously jumped to dance with them. Unfortunately, when we were leaving they played the Gangnam Style, which would have been TOP to dance!!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once it was dark we said byebye to Meliha and went back to KhaoSan Rd where I saw a guy selling fried bugs and I couldn&amp;rsquo;t wait to try some. The big scorpion was 100 baths which I reduced to 50 (1.3€) using my underdeveloped haggling skills (I could have gotten a better price, but I&amp;rsquo;m still working on it).
If you wonder how it tastes&amp;hellip; Quite tasteless, just crunchy and some kind of sandy texture. .
So before calling it a day we met 2 friends of Tessa and ate the typical and delicious Pad Thai with some drinks while we planned what was next in day 2.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;bonus-family-in-my-backpack&#34;&gt;BONUS: FAMILY in my backpack&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can call me crazy, and probably you will be right. But after all their dedication and support, I wanted to share this big trip with my family. They couldn&amp;rsquo;t leave Spain but I decided to bring them with me&amp;hellip; in an unorthodox fashion.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have their souls under the protection of my backpack, always close to me. And in some of the most remarkable landmarks of my trip, I ask to my travel buddies or random people that there may be around, to become my family, so I can share with them these nice memories.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;day-3-the-lucky-day-1022019&#34;&gt;Day 3: The Lucky Day (1/02/2019)&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After a futile attempt of making friends at my hostel, I decided to wander alone around the streets of Bangkok.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At some point,a friendly Thai guy approached me, and even though my Spider-senses were tingling, we engaged in a nice conversation. He told me about how today was &amp;ldquo;the lucky day&amp;rdquo; due to the anniversary of the King and something related to Buddha. Reason of all the yellow flags around the city. And to celebrate, all the temples were entry-free+there were specific tuk-tuks (with a yellow flag) subsidized to move people around the temples for only 40 Baht(~1€).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Before I could realize of what was going on, I was in one of this tuk-tuks heading towards an isolated area of the city where a &amp;ldquo;lucky-Buddha&amp;rdquo; was supposed to be.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;During the ride I was able to realize that something was off and I was in the middle of being scammed. My brain was racing to find a way to get out of there, when I just see another foreigner approaching.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The idea was to befriend him to have an excuse and leave the place without my tuk-tuk driver, when I realize this person was @jonnnyse the german guy that I just met the night before. It turns out he was in the middle of the same scam, and together we managed to figure out a way of escaping without upsetting our drivers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once we were out of the this tricky situation we went to visit more temples (which btw were not free), while laughing about what just happened to us and how odd had been to meet there.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We stop and chilled for a bit at the top of the Golden Mount where we met a group of friendly young people, gathered for a &amp;ldquo;United World&amp;rdquo; convention, who were very interested on talking to us.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To give end to our last day in Bangkok, Jonnie and I met with Tess and her friends to enjoy a red sky at the pier illuminated by the sunset, and we crossed the river for a last visit of Wat Arum at night.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We grabbed some dinner and went to the house by the river of a Western family that had invited us to drink with them. We played cards, took a dip at midnight in their outdoor swimming pool and said goodbye to each other as our paths separated next day.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://jasoromir.github.io/portfolio/hobbies/travelling&#34;&gt;Go back to travel directory&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chiang Mai</title>
      <link>https://jasoromir.github.io/portfolio/blog_travel/1thailand/chiangmai/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 May 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jasoromir.github.io/portfolio/blog_travel/1thailand/chiangmai/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;day-8-chiang-mai-07022019&#34;&gt;Day 8: Chiang Mai (07/02/2019)&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The bus that brought me to Chiang Mai looked more like a disco than a real bus. Green and violet lights would turn on every couple of minutes, which made it very difficult to get any sleep. Finally, I reached the city at 5a, and compared with the southern places I had been&amp;hellip;the north is cold, cold, cold at night.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Despite the tiredness, cold and my heavy backpack, for the first time I didn&amp;rsquo;t have anything to do or anywhere to go. So I ignored all the tuk-tuk drivers that offered me a ride to the city and decided to walk for 7km.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The travesie was well worth, as when I was crossing the Nawarat bridge I got delighted by the first sunrise of my trip.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I kept walking through the city, until I randomly found a nice looking hostel, where I would try to chill and do nothing for the rest of the morning.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was determined to shift my mindset from &amp;ldquo;I cannot stop moving for a second&amp;rdquo; to &amp;ldquo;Let&amp;rsquo;s just chill and go with the flow&amp;rdquo;. But a happy coincidence just happened, @lilian, whom I had met before in Lopburi had also just arrived to Chiang Mai. That saved the day because I was really struggling at not doing anything. So we decided to meet and chill together.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Number one option to chill in Thailand&amp;hellip;go get a Thai massage! Specifically we went to an exprisoner women center, which is a great initiative to enable women that have been in jail to get a remunerated job.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My masseuse was a small young lady, but she had incredible strength and made me see the stars by pressuring key points of my legs and crunching every bone and muscle of my back.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After the intense massage session, we went for a more western way of chilling drinking beer and playing pool at Lillian&amp;rsquo;s hostel. Here, we booked a 3 days trekking tour with homestay in different Hill tribe villages for the upcoming days.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And to finish the day, we went to watch a Muay Thai combat. I couldn&amp;rsquo;t tell the age of the fighters but even though they looked very young, they went all-in to punch and kick each other. One of them ended up with a broken eyebrow, other with a twisted arm, and most of the others knocked out on the floor.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;day-13-14-do-you-even-backpack&#34;&gt;DAY 13-14: Do you even backpack?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For the next couple of days, I was on my own. Funny enough, it was the first time since I left home. The hostel in which I had spent the previous night was fully booked, and I wasn&amp;rsquo;t sure where to go next. So I grabbed my big backpack with all my stuff and went into exploration mode (let me tell you, not the smartest idea!🤦‍♂️). While I was strolling through Chiang Mai, I couldn&amp;rsquo;t resist stopping in several of the hundreds of unique temples that decorate the city.
Thanks to &amp;lsquo;my highly developed extroverted skills&amp;rsquo;, I was too sacred of talking to people. So for that day it was just me, my phone, and trash containers that I used as elevation points to take &amp;lsquo;selfies&amp;rsquo;.📸 After two or three hours of sun and sweat walking from the North Gate to the South Gate of the fortressed city, I couldn&amp;rsquo;t walk anymore. I stopped to enjoy the typical northern dish (Khao Soi) in a Mama&amp;rsquo;s stand. I found my self a hostel and stayed there just chilling for the rest of the evening.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Next day, I had learned my lesson, I left the backpack at the hostel and rented a bicycle to move faster through the city. I was still a bit scared of renting a motorbike (since I had never driven one before). Even driving a regular bicycle through the chaotic traffic of Chiang Mai was scary as F!🚴‍♂️ I left the city whistling &amp;lsquo;Verano Azul&amp;rsquo; (only Spaniards will get the reference), while cycling through beautiful and green fields on the outskirts of CM. Finally, I arrived in a lake with several gigantic straw statues of different animals, including the majestic King Kong (not our previous guide but the gorilla🦍). I gather some of my courage and asked for my characteristic family picture. The problem was that the tourists around the area were Chinese who did not speak English, so it took me a long while until they understood what I wanted. They liked the idea tho, and they also took pictures with their cameras while still using the masks (Now, surely my family is decorating random Chinese houses).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://jasoromir.github.io/portfolio/hobbies/travelling&#34;&gt;Go back to travel directory&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chiang Rai</title>
      <link>https://jasoromir.github.io/portfolio/blog_travel/1thailand/chiangrai/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 May 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jasoromir.github.io/portfolio/blog_travel/1thailand/chiangrai/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;day-25-28-chiang-rai-temples&#34;&gt;DAY 25-28: Chiang Rai Temples&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The next morning I didn&amp;rsquo;t eat anything to avoid the vomiting sensation that was about to come from navigating the serpent-like road to Chiang Mai. There, I took another bus to Chiang Rai, and fell asleep. When I woke up the bus had stopped in the middle of the road, it was already dark, and we were still quite far from Chiang Rai.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;More than an hour later, I was starving. Nobody knew when we would resume our way, so I couldn&amp;rsquo;t resist anymore and stepped out of the bus to find something to eat. As soon as a local lady was serving me a soup, the bus engine got fix (damn Murphy&amp;rsquo;s Law!). It was funny that the local lady immediately poured the soup from the bowl into a plastic bag and handed it to me (one year later and I still have not learned how to eat soup from a plastic bag without making a big mess).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The following morning I met with Ella (one of the members from the farm family) who had also come to Chiang Rai, and we visited the three main attractions of the small town (white temple, blue temple, and black house).
First, we took a local bus to go to Wat Rong Khun a.k.a. the white temple.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Actually, it is not a temple, but a piece of art funded and designed by the famous Thai artist Chalermchai Kositpipat. They often compare it to the Sagrada Familia in Barcelona, as the artist has not finished it yet and it will take decades before that happens.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I will not bore you with more details that you can find in Wikipedia, but this temple has so many details, and it is so unique, I believe is worth visiting it 100%. To come back we had to stand in the middle of the road until a small pick up truck brought us back to town. Since there was no space for everybody inside the small vehicle I had to ride it local style, standing outside, hanging from the metal bars.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Next, we went to Baan Dam (not the actor) but the museum also known as the Black House. This museum has a bit of an obscure aura, decorated with a broad collection of skins, bones, teeth, and horns of a wide array of animals. I didn&amp;rsquo;t like it that much, so rapidly we went into the last attraction.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This time, we had to run into a bus in the middle of the road, avoiding the traffic, as there were no bus stops and we already had missed two. One more time, no space for me, so I had to sit on the floor, next to the driver, bumping my as in every pothole of the road.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The blue temple (Wat Rong Suea Ten) is also one of the most beautiful and unique temples I have seen in Thailand. It was constructed very recently, and the designer is one of the students of Chalermchai (the designer of the white temple). Wikipedia for more info.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To finish the day we went to a roof top bar and see the sunset. There we met an American expat with a hyperactive kid. He was giving us some advice of what to do in the following days and I was entertaining the kid with a magic trick involving a coin that I learned form my dad🎩. We moved all together to a reggae bar, until the kid absorbed all my energies and I felt sleep.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Chiang Rai post will continue, as I could recover more pictures and stories to tell. Today is spam day. And last one in Thailand.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;day-25-28-chiang-rai-nature&#34;&gt;DAY 25-28: Chiang Rai Nature&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We rented bikes for the following two days to visit Chiang Rai surroundings.
Another girl that Ella had met in her hostel joined us. She had been dating a Thai guy for two years and she could speak the language, which was quite useful to communicate with locals.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first day we went to the South. We spent most of the day in a park with many different kinds of flowers. I don&amp;rsquo;t remember much about that park, only that food was very expensive, and (from the only picture I have recovered) that yellow flowers🌻 fit fabulously on me🤣.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After that, we went waterfall hunting, but it was getting late and we had to settle for a refreshing deep on the river.
On the way back to Chiang Rai we stopped to have dinner in a restaurant that had tables floating on the river. To finish the day, we went to observe a light spectacle at the clock tower in the main square of the town. Thousands of birds were flying around the lights of the tower. With the dark background of the night, it felt even more magical, like if they were dancing stars💫 .&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The last day we went North. We were supposed to find a small village where people live in harmony with elephants🐘, but the elephants that we saw were in chains so we left the place rapidly. We kept going up the road, driving through hills covered with rice paddies of an intense green color that didn&amp;rsquo;t seem real.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We were hoping to find natural hot springs to chill and spend the afternoon. Once again we were disappointed with what we found. The hot springs were there, but they stink to sulfur and were boiling hot🔥 .
At some point, we heard some noises and we found that the hot springs reached a river where local kids were playing. We spent the rest of the day swimming with them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On the way back we stop for sunset next to the rice paddies. That was the goodbye to Thailand.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://jasoromir.github.io/portfolio/hobbies/travelling&#34;&gt;Go back to travel directory&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Kanchanaburi</title>
      <link>https://jasoromir.github.io/portfolio/blog_travel/1thailand/kanchanaburi/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 May 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jasoromir.github.io/portfolio/blog_travel/1thailand/kanchanaburi/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;day-4-erawan-waterfalls-02022019&#34;&gt;Day 4: Erawan Waterfalls (02/02/2019)&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Before heading to the North part of Thailand, Tess and I decided to visit one more city from the middle region. We spent most of our forth day in a very slow bus with direction to Kanchanaburi.
The city is mainly known for historical events during WWII described in the book and movie with the title &amp;ldquo;Bridge on the river Kwai&amp;rdquo;. It is also very close to some amazing waterfalls. However, not many western people visit the area.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once we arrived, in our dorm we met François, a french guy travelling alone with his motorbike. And together we planned how to organize the following days.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Next morning we had to wake up early, go to the middle of the road, and hail a bus that would take us to the Erawan Waterfalls. At that time, I was expecting the bus to be empty, but on the contrary, there were no space left to sit. Until a friendly monk in the back of the bus made signs for me to get closer, created space so I could seat next to him. We echanged smiles and he went back to sleep.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Erawan Waterfalls are composed by 7 different levels, with only two things in common: clear turquoise water and curious fishes that loved to swim next to you, and even nibble the skin of your feet if you stand still.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To reach each level we had to do some hiking. And even though it was recommended to do use proper shoes I decided to go &amp;ldquo;tarzan-mode&amp;rdquo; and do it barefoot.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After a full day of swimming with fishes, climbing some lianas, doing yoga poses under a big waterfall, and running after monkeys through the jungle, I needed a feet massage. So we chilled with our feet in the water while small fishes gave us a free peeling session (it took me at least 15 min to get used to it).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When it started to go dark, we said good bye to François who was going deeper into the National park with his motorbike, and we got the bus to come back. Once again there was no space for me, and this time I had to sit in the middle of the bus corridor, next to the driver. Some bumpy roads msde me think I would go flying through the windshield, but thanfully I made it in one piece to enjoy delicious local food at Kanchanaburi&amp;rsquo;s night market.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;bonus-family-in-my-backpack&#34;&gt;BONUS: FAMILY in my backpack&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First time I asked Thai people to wear the masks of my family. Curious fact, they fight each other because they all wanted to wear female masks&amp;hellip; Is my dad so ugly? Or maybe it was the excitement of being a ladyboy for a couple of minutes? 😅&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;day-6-the-death-railway&#34;&gt;DAY 6: The Death Railway&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The most popular feature of Kanchanaburi is the bridge over the river Kwai, and the numerous memorials to the prisoners of war who died building the Burma railway.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Today&amp;rsquo;s plan was to ride a train through the &amp;ldquo;Death Railway&amp;rdquo; starting at the famous bridge all the way to Hellfire pass. To get a better idea of what happened there, the night before I spent a couple of hours reading some interesting facts and watching the 1957 movie.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once in the train, I had the chance to throw some random comments in front of a couple of americans, that amazed by my &amp;ldquo;wikipedia knowledge&amp;rdquo;, wanted to hire me as their guide for the day.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The bridge in itself is not a big deal. In fact, it is not even similar to the one displayed in the movie (which was recorded in Sri Lanka). That is a bit disappointing. However, there is a part of the trajectory that runs between a river and a clift where the views are spectacular. Furthermore, since there is only one train every 3 hours, people are allowed to walk through the rails and enjoy the views.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Something to highlight is that next to this train station I eat the best coconut ice cream ever!!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Back in the hostel I still had some cravings for fruit, so I bought a whole pineapple (my favorite fruit in Thailand so far) for 50 cents and they taught me how to cut it Thai style.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Later, we had dinner with 3 new people from our dorm and one of them told us how easy had been for him to hitchhike everywhere in the SE of Asia&amp;hellip;Now I want to try it too!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;day-7-a-bike-ride&#34;&gt;DAY 7: A Bike Ride&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our last day in Kanchanaburi, Tess and I rented bicycles (we were a bit afraid of renting scooters) to do a 40 km exploration tour around the surrounding areas of the city.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At first, it felt kind of dangerous to jump into the road, where all the cars and motorbikes didn&amp;rsquo;t seem to respect any traffic law. Especially, because my bike didn&amp;rsquo;t have breaks and I had to stop by setting on fire the sole of my shoes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, as soon as I got used to drive on the left side, I realized that despite the dominant and aggressive &amp;ldquo;Thai way&amp;rdquo; of driving, they are really aware of everything going on and I felt completely safe.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In our first stop we ride our bikes through an out-of-use small version of hellfire memorial.
Then, with the bikes on our shoulders we climbed several steps to reach a viewpoint over the river Kwae.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the mid point of our journey we found a gigantic monkey pod tree. At this point Tessa wanted to go back to the city, but I was determined to complete the circuit, so we splited ways.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;During the rest of the way, I waved &amp;ldquo;hello&amp;rdquo; to every local I met, which almost cost me falling from the bike a couple of times. Surprised of seeing me riding a bicycle on the bumpy and boiling hot roads, they laughed while waving back.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In fact, I got severely burned, but the dragon themed temples of Ban Tham &amp;amp; Than Phaet temples, located in the top of two mountains, made it all worth. .
After the intense work out to get to the top of the mountains I only wanted a relaxing ride back while enjoying the views. But a group of dogs, well prepared to bite my legs, decided against it and chased me for a long time. .
The worst part is that when I finally lost them, my back tire exploded. And even though some locals tried to help me, I had to pull my bike back for at least 30 min.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When I arrived to the hostel, I met a group of cool guys from USA and Switzerland. And before taking a night bus towards my first city of the North (Chiang Mai) , we spent the rest of the afternoon sharing experiences while eating refreshing pineapple.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://jasoromir.github.io/portfolio/hobbies/travelling&#34;&gt;Go back to travel directory&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lahu Homestay</title>
      <link>https://jasoromir.github.io/portfolio/blog_travel/1thailand/lahu/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 May 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jasoromir.github.io/portfolio/blog_travel/1thailand/lahu/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;day-10-homestay-with-the-lahu&#34;&gt;DAY 10: HOMESTAY WITH THE LAHU🎄&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It has been more than a year since I started my backpacking adventure, and almost the same time since I stopped updating my journal.
I found all kinds of excuses not to plasm my thoughts into &amp;lsquo;paper&amp;rsquo;, but today something clicked. Today, I have decided to commit to this exercise of introspection and dig into my memories to bring back the main highlights of yhis last year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this entry, I resume the journey at Chiang Mai. That morning, my french friend @lilian.aoust and I got up early to embark on a 3 days expedition into the nearby mountains. We thought we would be part of a large group but it ended up being just the 2 of us. On the way there, we stopped to do water rafting, which sounded very promising but ended up being quite disappointing as the river was no more than a couple feet deep, and the boat moved extremely slow.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Soon after, we got introduced to our guide, King Kong, who guided us through a short hike into one of the villages that inhabit those remote hills. There, they assigned us to a family that would host us for the following nights. What made it interesting was that the only English word they could pronounce was &amp;lsquo;&amp;lsquo;Hello&amp;rsquo;&amp;rsquo; whenever they wanted to catch our attention. King Kong was our only chance of communicating with them, but he didn&amp;rsquo;t stick around for too long.
Nevertheless, we had a great time. We watched the sunset while getting a Thai massage from one of the elders of the tribe, I woke up with the roosters to see the sunrise, we hiked, and I tried for the first time drinking water from a river using my LifeStraw (it sucked!). The rest of the time, I mainly played with the kids of the family, helping them with some English homework and learning about the different minorities that inhabit Thailand. In particular, we were in a village of the Lahu, and coincidentally, that night, they were celebrating their New Year.
We gathered around a stick in the middle of the main square. The kids played with fire crackers, the elder played some weird looking instruments and the rest, we danced in circles for hours.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Before we left I asked them for a family picture :)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://jasoromir.github.io/portfolio/hobbies/travelling&#34;&gt;Go back to travel directory&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mindful Farm</title>
      <link>https://jasoromir.github.io/portfolio/blog_travel/1thailand/farm/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 May 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jasoromir.github.io/portfolio/blog_travel/1thailand/farm/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;day-15-20-farmville&#34;&gt;DAY 15-20: Farmville&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After my first 2 weeks of moving around, I wanted to find a place to settle and give something back.
After some research, I applied for volunteering in a mindful farm🌽. I received an email with confusing instructions on how to get into a secondary farm. As the rest of the people were moving there too. After hours waiting for a &amp;lsquo;bus&amp;rsquo; that I thought wasn&amp;rsquo;t coming, and a ride with confused locals staring at me, I finally got dropped in the middle of the road next to a temple.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I started to walk up and down the road with the hope of seeing some sign pointing me to the farm, nothing! I tried not to panic and go back to the empty-looking temple, hoping that someone would show up.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At some point, I called the attention of a monk, who after some sign language communication showed me a path through the jungle which would lead me to the farm. After 5 min walking the path I heard one dog barking, a few seconds later I was surrounded by more than 20 dogs barking, and me, almost shitting myself on the spot💩. It felt like an eternity standing there not knowing what to do until some locals came to my rescue. They took me to the farm, where there were only locals who didn&amp;rsquo;t speak English. I started to panic, the following days were going to be rough!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of these locals was very friendly and using a phone app he tried to teach me some farm stuff. We gather red flowers from banana trees, banana tree stem, and some roots similar to potatoes.
After the farm work, he took me with his bike to an area with hot springs where we boiled eggs into the hot waters. Then he asked me if I wanted to go to the temple. I thought he wanted me to pray, so I explained to him I am not religious, but that I would join him if he wanted to go.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After a brief ride, we were back in the temple, and when we entered one of the buildings I almost cried when I saw a group of another 20 international volunteers that had finally arrived😭. Yuhuuu!!🥳🙌&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There we would meet Pi Nan, a former monk that married a Japanese woman and now they dedicated their lives in developing these mindful farms.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For the following days, most of us would live at basic rooms on the monastery, except Pi Nan and me. We lived next to each other on the farm, in &amp;lsquo;luxurious&amp;rsquo; open-air rooms of 1 m2 with a &amp;lsquo;bed&amp;rsquo; made out of bamboo (I must have been his favorite! it was such an honor to experience the let go of all the comfort🙏).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Despite the painful nights, I felt such a great connection with everybody in the community that the long hours under the sun doing farm work didn&amp;rsquo;t seem that hard. Pi Nan also instructed in meditation and mindfulness. Some of the tasks included sweeping all the leaves from the monastery (so much fun!🧹🍂), and eating in silence (that was hard for a Spanish guy). One of the monks of the monastery also wanted to contribute to our education and a couple of nights was talking to us about the &amp;lsquo;teachings of the Buddha&amp;rsquo; (I&amp;rsquo;m good - I&amp;rsquo;m God - no good is good - good is God, think about that🙄).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After several days of intense work, most of us were ready to move on, and we decided to keep our adventure together in Pai.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://jasoromir.github.io/portfolio/hobbies/travelling&#34;&gt;Go back to travel directory&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pai</title>
      <link>https://jasoromir.github.io/portfolio/blog_travel/1thailand/pai/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 May 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jasoromir.github.io/portfolio/blog_travel/1thailand/pai/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;day-21-24-the-farm-gang-moves-to-pai&#34;&gt;DAY 21-24: The Farm Gang moves to Pai.&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Next morning Darila(@darila_ ), Hippo (@hippolyte.v), and me, decided to hitchhike back to Chiang Mai👍.
Despite my sexy pose, Hippo was the one that got a Thai lady to give us a ride. She did speak that much English, but she was super excited to have us aboard. She did not only drop us at the bus station, but also came to help us buy the tickets to Pai, all in exchange for a picture together.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The ride between Chaing Mai and Pai was intense, 762 vomit-inducing curves🤮 (little did I know that I would be repeating that trip a couple more times in the future). Until now, I had resisted being another tourist buying elephant baggy pants or t-shirts. But somehow Pai influenced me. Pai is considered the Thai hippie paradise, with a laid-back atmosphere, a fire circus, lots of yoga, delicious food, and surrounded by beautiful nature.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The hippie vibe started to grow on me (like my hair and my beard🧔), and I ended up getting my first Aladin pants and elephant tank top🧞. Another first experience to add in Pai was driving a bike (followed by my first accident too, but that will come later).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I wanted to drive a scooter for a long time, but I kept hearing negative opinions on how dangerous the roads are in Thailand, how the Thai police are there to get you if you don&amp;rsquo;t have the correct driver&amp;rsquo;s license, etc. However, Philip (@so_ein_baertiger_tuep), who had come from Chiang Mai to Pai driving a rented bike, convinced me to give it a try letting me his. I will be eternally grateful as that moment changed my whole trip🛵.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For the following days, the farm gang (Dilara, Hippo, Philip, Yvonne (@yvonnevanzyl1) and Ella) would rent our own bikes and went exploring Pai&amp;rsquo;s surrounding areas. A traditional Chinese village (tourist trap, they scummed us in the only restaurant and threatened us to call the police if we did not pay), waterfalls (sadly they were a bit dry), the Land Split, the Pai WWII memorial bridge, and the two most iconic highlights the Withe Buddha, and the Pai Canyon.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, the best memories of those days in Pai are all the moments we spent together, connecting (since on the farm we were too busy working and eating mindfully), watching sunsets and sunrises and making the promise that even our journeys would split soon we would meet again🌄.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But, wait!! What happened with the motorbike accident?💥
I have to admit it was my fault, after the first day driving, I felt so secure of my skills that I permitted myself to constantly check the phone while driving to look at the map. Surprisingly, that was not the cause of the accident, but it gave me a false sense of security.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It was Philip last day and we went far North to enjoy a relaxing day of hot springs. They turned out to be quite expensive so we decided to go to a random location of the map that also pointed to a hot spring. We ended up in a semi-abandoned village, we trespassed into a local&amp;rsquo;s farm (as the map indicated that was the way) and kept walking until someone caught us and asked us to leave (it didn&amp;rsquo;t seem we were going to find the hot spring anyway).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On the way back, we found a police control, I was a bit/lot scared💩 as I don&amp;rsquo;t have any kind of driving license, luckily they were only looking for drugs and we could resume our paths.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All the excitement made us hungry, and we were looking for a place to stop and eat. I saw one, and turned my head back for 3 sec to point the rest of the gang that we could stop there. Those 3 sec were enough for my bike to deviate left, towards a big patch of sand, lose control of my bike, fall on the road, and be droved over by Hippo who was a bit too close to me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Luckily I only got some scratches and injured my wrists for the following month. It was a good wake up call to be more conscious while on the road, but it did not stop me from keep driving bikes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That last day Philip reminded us how powerful it is to compliment each other, so we shared beautiful and positive words before saying good bye.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://jasoromir.github.io/portfolio/hobbies/travelling&#34;&gt;Go back to travel directory&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ayutthaya</title>
      <link>https://jasoromir.github.io/portfolio/blog_travel/1thailand/ayutthaya/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 May 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jasoromir.github.io/portfolio/blog_travel/1thailand/ayutthaya/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;day-2-the-old-capital-30012019&#34;&gt;Day 2: The old capital (30/01/2019)&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The next day we woke up early to catch a train to Ayutthaya first time in the morning.
At that time, I still had the chance to distinguish several drunk foreigners going back to their &amp;ldquo;caves&amp;rdquo; in the good company of their exotic ladyboys.
.
After meeting with Tessa and some failed haggle attempts with taxi drivers we got to the train station. Two hours later we arrived to Ayutthaya, the old capital of the Thai Kingdom, sacked and almost forgotten around 300 years ago, where we met with Tessa&amp;rsquo;s friends Louise and Emma. A great advantage of being 4 was the possibility of splitting the price of hiring a tuk-tuk (my first tuk-tuk) so they would move or lazy asses from one temple to the next one.
.
Less shiny, that their Bangkok counterparts, Wat Mahathat and Wat Chaiwatthanaram display the weathered and colossal buildings, now in ruins, that once upon a time constituted the grand palace of the Kingdom. And as a lover of the pointy chedis, my personal favorite could not be other than Wat Phra Sri Sanphet, with the must-do Yoga &amp;ldquo;postureo&amp;rdquo;.
.
After 4 hours of temples we recovered some energies in the most traditional noodles place of town and spontaneously decided to grab a train towards the neighboring town, Lopburi.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;bonus-family-in-my-backpack&#34;&gt;BONUS: FAMILY in my backpack&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Second delivery of pictures with my family👨‍👩‍👧‍👦.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This time was easier to get the photos. I didn&amp;rsquo;t require to ask strangers to wear the masks and pose with me, since I could just abuse from my traveling companions😁&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;day-2-jumanji-30012019&#34;&gt;Day 2: Jumanji (30/01/2019)&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The main characteristic of this small town is that it&amp;rsquo;s inhabitants are a bit special. You don&amp;rsquo;t need to walk more than 5 min from the station to feel you have entered the movie Jumanji, as the streets are dominated by wild monkeys.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In particular, they have made the old temple of Phra Pang Sam Got their home, and they won&amp;rsquo;t hesitate to jump on you to steal as many of your belongings they can grab. I wanted to get a couple of them on me for the laughs, but knowing my luck on these matters I could see myself going back home with rabies the second day of my trip. However, there we met @lilian.aoust a joyful solo traveler that seemed to enjoy the company of our far cousins.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After spending the afternoon together, Tess and I went back to Bangkok, and met with Louise for some drinks before calling it a day, where we met Jonny the last member of the gang!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://jasoromir.github.io/portfolio/hobbies/travelling&#34;&gt;Go back to travel directory&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
